NGUYEN TUAN ANH

Gender : Male

Birthday: 01/10/1993

Marital status: Married

Nationality: Vietnamese

Country: Vietnam



Phone number 0931433272

PLC/HMI & Robot programming, Industrial/Process Engineer

Email

tuananh.bku@gmail.com

Address

Ha Huy Giap, Go Vap District, Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

OBJECTIVES

Hi everybody,

My name is Nguyen Tuan Anh, a young man born and raised in a poor countryside in the Central region called Quang Tri.

I graduated with a Bachelor's degree in Automation and Control Engineering from Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology and started working from 2016.

Up to now, I have more than 7 years of experience working in the field of Factory Automation, Global Manufacturing, especially the Automotive field.

In addition, I have experience working abroad such as Japan, China, Europe (Poland, Serbia...), which makes me more confident to adapt to various pressures and also new environments.

During that time, I mainly focused on 2 majors:

- · Electrical design, PLC/HMI programming.
- · NPI (New Product Introduction), launching new production line.

(For more details, please refer to below)

I have worked abroad for many years, so I hope that in the near future I will find a job in Vietnam, specifically Ho Chi Minh City, to soon stabilize my life and further develop my career path.

SKILLS

Electrical AutoCAD Industrial Engineer

Electric and Automation

Design

Traceability System

PLC/HMI Programming



EXPERIENCE

Year(s) of Experiment: 7

Current Level: Experienced (Non - Manager)

04/2021 - Now

Industrial/Process Engineer - Nidec Corporation Global - Full time

Working in Nidec Shiga Technical Center(ST/C), but most of the time is on support work at the group's factories on global, especially in China, Europe (Serbia, Poland).

Main task is to support the launch of a new production line for

EPS motor of AMEC (Automotive Motor & Electronic Control Business),

Details:

- 1. Prepare PPAP documents: 3 major(Flow Chart, Control Plan, PFMEA), Equipment checksheet, ...
- 2. Doing Equipment Evaluation(MSA) at Phase 3 and 4 of APQP on-site.
- 3. Apply traceability system(PQM/NTRS) onsite, which is used for tracking and quality monitoring.
- 4. Improve OEE, especially Cycle time of current running line.

Skills: PQM/NTRS · Advanced Product Quality Planning (APQP) · Production Part Approval Process (PPAP) · Equipment Evaluation · Production Operations · Traceability

02/2020 - 04/2021

Standard Engineer - Nidec Corporation Global - Full time

Standardization for Global production line of NIDEC Factory.

- 1. Make format for Standard documents: Equipment Common Specifications, Maintenance, Layout, ...
- 2. Support, modify and update some applications created by VBA, JavaScripts to manage projects.
- 3. Prepare standard equipment which is used for producing Prototype samples.

Skills: Technical Standards · Standards-based · Visual Basic for Applications (VBA) · JavaScript · PLC Programming

12/2017 - 02/2020

Research and Development Engineer - Nidec Corporation Global - Full time

Design Automation machines for 5 Nidec Factories in Saigon High Tech Park, District 9.

Receiving requests from customer - Deploying concept with Mechanical team - Quoting products price, especially in Electrical Field and Software programming.

Skills: Vision System · HMI Programming · AutoCAD Electrical · Electrical Design · PLC Programming

10/2016 - 12/2017

Electrical Engineering Intern - Nidec Corporation Global - Full time

Training about Factory Automation: Electrical design and PLC/HMI programming, also Robot application for Automation Line

Especially actual experience to build a new production line at Nidec Machinery Factory in Pinghu, Zhejiang (China).

Skills: Vision System · HMI Programming · AutoCAD Electrical · Electrical Design · PLC Programming

03/2016 - 10/2016

Pre Post Sales Engineer - ITD Corporation - Full time

- · Design electrical drawings using AutoCAD 2D software.
- · Creation of documentation: Product and project manuals/instructions.
- · Creation of BOM, support team Sale for bidding.

Skills: Intelligence Transportation \cdot CCTV Installation \cdot Bid Preparation \cdot AutoCAD

EDUCATION

Highest Degree Level: Bachelor

School: Ho Chi Minh University of Technology

Degree: Bachelor

Graduated in: 04/2016

Description:

LANGUAGES

English

Level: Normal

Certification: TOEIC 775

Japan

Level: Normal

Certification: JLPT N2

CAREER INFORMATION

Level: Team Leader / Supervisor

Salary: 1.000 - 2.000 USD

Job type: Full time

Industry: Mechanical / Auto / Automotive,

Electrical / Electronics Location: Ho Chi Minh